Welcome back.
So in this section, we are going to create an Android system service.
Okay.
So here are the steps which we have to follow to create a system service.
So in the first step, we create the service manager, and then we create a service class and then basically
just add the service and then compile.
And so and we check whether the service is running or not.
Okay.
So in the first part, actually, you are creating a service manager class.
So the service manager class is nothing, but it's a manager of this, obviously.
It actually instructs the service class to run a function.
Okay.
You can match it to a real world manager who actually instructs his colleague to do something.
So similarly in service manager, this instructs the service class to do something.
Okay.
And then we have the ideal file here.
So for now, just keep in mind that the ideal is nothing but just an interface which is actually used
to create a android service manager.
Okay.
So I'll show you the process on how to create that.
And then in the second part is actually the creation of the service file itself.
So far, service file is actually the place where you write the actual functionality.
So in our case, this is a very simple system service which actually brings something to the log.
And in the third part is actually the registration of the service, so that his creation has to be done
in these three files, basically.
The first one is the system service registry and the context and then the system.
So.
And then finally you had to compile and check whether the service is running or not by using ADB.
Okay.
So that's that was a very quick overview of what exactly we are going to do.
And in the next tutorial I will just walk you through the code.
And later we go ahead and implement it.
Okay.
Thank you.